PERSONAL INFORMATION

Mario Romano

- ₹50C Gascony Avenue, NW6 4NE, London
- **i** +447577282762 (please before call me arrange via email. Don't leave messages on my voicemail, email is prefered)
- mario.romano83@gmail.com
- in http://www.linkedin.com/pub/mario-romano/14/6a7/51a

Online Portfolio: http://magemello.github.io/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/MagemelloMario

Sex Male | Date of birth 16 September 1983 | Nationality Italian

SUMMARY AND KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

I'm Director of Engineering in Alfresco but I'm still really much involved with coding and product strategy. In Alfresco I helped the company to grow the London team from 3 developers to 40 developers, creating a really motivated team focused on delivering value. I have also helped the company accelerating the development phase establishing good practices like: scrum, continuous delivery, TDD, peer review, clean coding and automation testing. Before Alfresco, I have accumulated nearly 10 years of experience in developing software for large organisations and startups. I'm also the author of the Packt video course series about Angular 2 and Spring 5, I like to speak to conferences, contribute to open source projects and passionate about microservices and blockchain.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

September 2002 to March 2007 Bachelor's degree: Computer Science and Engineering.

University: University of Naples Federico II, Italy.

Grade: 88/110

Thesis and Internship: Gaming, Social Network Integration.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, JavaEE, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Android, HTML, CSS, SQL.

Frameworks: Spring, Guava, Dropwizard, Backbone, Angular, Angular 2, Hibernate, Bootstrap, Material Design.

Databases: Mysql, Oracle, H2, MongoDB, Neo4j, OrientDb.

Build Tools: Maven, Ant, Gradle.

Practices: SCRUM, Agile, Tribe, TDD, Clean coding, Pair programming, Continuous delivery.

Architectures: Microservices, Single Page Application, REST, Client/Server.

IDE: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Android Studio.

Version control: Git . Clear case.

Cloud application platform: Heroku, AWS, Parse.

Others: Redis, Riak, Bower, Grunt, Npm, Node, Handlebar, Jenkins, Guice, Docker, Rancher, Travis and kubernetes.

Operating systems: Linux, Osx, Windows.

WORK EXPERIENCE

December 2016 to Cutrent Job

Employer: Alfresco

Role: Director of Engineering

Projects: Activiti BPM and Application development framework

Responsibilities:

- Translate product strategy & roadmap into high quality and maintainable product.
- Develop and manage end-to-end project plans and ensure

- on-time delivery.
- Communicate status, data and metrics of all the projects to the internal and external stakeholders..
- Lead technical discussions and have an understanding of the underlying rationale for technical decisions.
- Identify gaps and issues in the release process and drive long term improvement
- Oversee agile processes such as Scrum and Kanban
- Promote best engineering practices like clean coding, tdd, continuous delivery, automation testing.
- Oversee effective prioritization and optimisation of resources
- Help the company to evolve and improve engineering practices
- Build, inspire & grow high performing development teams
- Help engineer members in achieving their career goals
- Establish a supportive, collaborative, and fulfilling place where engineers can progress their career and use their passion and creativity to build the best product
- Encourage and promote open source culture and actively participate in the open source community.

Technologies: java EE, spring, mysql, riak, javascript, css, html, bootstrap, material design, angular, angular 2, webpack, karma handlebar, grunt, bower, npm, node, json, continuous delivery. Tools: eclipse, intellij, git, jenkins, travis, docker and kubernetes. Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

May 2016 to December 2016 Employer: Alfresco

Role: Director of Engineer and Architect at Alfresco

Projects: Activiti BPM and Application development framework

Responsibilities:

- Architect in an on-going BPM project.
- Architect for a green field project, ADF.
- Integrate BPM and ECM.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new system integration.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities for the FE/BE application.
- Build a new team.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.
- Speaker to Alfresco conferences.

Technologies: java EE, spring, mysql, riak, javascript, css, html, bootstrap, material design, angular, angular 2, webpack, karma handlebar, grunt, bower, npm, node, json, continuous delivery. Tools: eclipse, intellij, git, jenkins, travis, docker.

Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

May 2015 to 2016

Employer: Alfresco Role: Team Lead Projects: Activiti BPM

Responsibilities:

- Key contributor in an on-going project to develop a new SPA.
- Integrate BPM and ECM.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities for the FE/BE application.
- Build a new team.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, spring, mysql, riak, javascript, css, html, bootstrap, angular, handlebar, grunt, bower, npm, json, continuous delivery.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

August 2013 to May 2015 **Employer:** Workshare

Role: Senior full stack developer

Projects: Professional (file sharing collaboration, similar to dropbox)

Responsibilities:

- Key contributor in an on-going project to develop a new CMS capable of handling large and ever increasing content volumes, bulding a new microservices architecture.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities for the FE/BE application.
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, microservices, guava guice, redis, mysql, riak, javascript, css, html, bootstrap, backbone, handlebar, grunt, bower, npm, json.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

Practices: Scrum, Tribe, TDD, Clean coding.

February 2013 to August 2013 Employer: ITHR Consulting. Role: Senior full stack developer.

Projects: MTD Internation Trading System. Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

Responsibilities:

Responsible for the design and implementation of new

- functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team, providing guidance and support resulting in an increase in productivity of 50%. Applied strong technical skills, expertly splitting complex problems and tasks into smaller parts to boost the Developer's confidence and optimise potential.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, spring, velocity, javascript, jquery, bootstrap,

html, css, apache.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

September 2012 to February 2013

Employer: ITHR Consulting.
Role: Senior software developer.
Projects: Vodafone Mobile Portal.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Personally fixed bugs.

Technologies: java EE, spring, velocity, javascript, jquery, bootstrap,

html, css, apache.

Tools: eclipse, git, jenkins.

Practices: Scrum, TDD, Clean coding.

March 2012 to August 2012

Employer: Accenture.

Role: Analyst /Software developer.

Projects: Eni Work Planning.

Responsibilities:

- Responsable of the FE and BE team (10 members).
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, struts2, hibernate, log4j, sql, javascript, jquery, ajax, html, css, oracle, Apache.

Tools: eclipse, clear case, clear quest, soapUI.

September 2011 to March 2012

Employer: Accenture.

Role: Analyst / Software developer.

Projects: Smart Mobile Social Network.

Responsibilities:

- Responsable of the FE and BE team (10 members).
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team.
- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: android, javavascript, ajax, html, css, jquery, json, wak. Tools: android studio, clear case, clear quest.

October 2008 to September 2011 Employer: Accenture.

Role: Analyst /Software developer.

Projects: Telecom Italy Top Business.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for the design and implementation of new functionalities, writing code and conducting integration tests.
- Effectively mentored the Junior Developer assigned to the team, providing guidance and support resulting in an increase in productivity of 50%. Applied strong technical skills, expertly splitting complex problems and tasks into smaller parts to boost the Developer's confidence and optimise potential.
- Actively involved in interviewing and hiring of new team members.

Technologies: java EE, struts2, hibernate, log4j, sql, javascript, jquery, ajax, html, css, oracle, Apache.

Tools: eclipse, clear case, clear quest, soapUI.

May 2008 to October 2008 Employer: Accenture.
Role: Software developer.
Projects: Generali Insurance.

Responsibilities:

 Personally fixed bugs and implemented improvement features using Java and J2EE on a large scale project.

Technologies: java EE, sql, oracle, clear case, clear quest, Apache.

Tools: eclipse, clear case.

March 2008 to May 2008 Employer: Accenture.
Role: Software developer.
Projects: FIAT auto portal.

Responsibilities:

• Personally fixed bugs and implemented improvement features using Java, J2EE, javascript and asp on a large scale project.

Technologies: java EE, javascript, asp, html, css, jboss.

Tools: eclipse, clear case.

January 2008 to March 2008 Employer: Accenture.
Role: Software developer.
Projects: Mediobanca.

Responsibilities:

- Write automation test for the new portal.
- Coaching to the other members of the team how to write automated test.

Technologies: java, junit.
Tools: eclipse, clear case.

PUBBLICATION

May 30, 2017

Pack Pub:

- Learning Web Application with Spring 5 and Angular 2
 - https://www.packtpub.com/application-development/le arning-web-application-spring-5-and-angular-2-video

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

Web Application developed by me: (included in Facebook start program)

 Facebook Drive: Facebook Drive is a personal cloud storage service that lets users store and synchronize digital content across computers, laptops and mobile devices, and share it with their facebook friends. (javascript, marionette, nodejs, MSDN rest api, backbone, grount, bower, html5, css3,

less, parse, heroku)

o https://apps.facebook.com/drivefb/

Library developed by me:

- Easy facebook android sdk, open source library to connect android to facebook. (java, android)
 - o www.easyfacebookandroidsdk.com

Android App developed by me:

- Easy Paint: paint. (java, android, asp, php)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.easy. paint
- Face off Movie: photo app. (java, android)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.face.o ff.movie.free
- Rage Meme Camera : photo app (java , android)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.troll.fa ce&feature=more_from_developer
- Marble Boing 3D : game App (java, android, unity)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gem. marbleboingfree
- Dice & Dragons 3D : dice simulation App (java , android , unity)
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gem. dicedragon
- Android Paper: rss feed reader (Easy Facebook api, java, android)
 - https://market.android.com/details?id=com.rss.androidpa per
- Real Football Italy: photo app. (java, android)
 - https://market.android.com/details?id=com.soccer.player .italy

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue Italian

Other languages English

Written: Good level Spoken: Good level